<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Burke Holland</title>
    <link>https://burkeholland.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Burke Holland</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 10:51:28 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://burkeholland.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GSAP, Webpack and invalid tweens</title>
      <link>https://burkeholland.github.io/posts/invalid-tween/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 10:51:28 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://burkeholland.github.io/posts/invalid-tween/</guid>
      <description>Before I forget, I wanted to document for posterity how I lost about 4 hours yesterday to gsap/webpack issue.
I was working on a Vue project (CLI) with some gsap powered animations that I did not write. Not having written them, I can confess that I have no idea what they are or what they do. Any time I see the word &amp;ldquo;Tween&amp;rdquo;, I get flashbacks to actual Flash timelines and this very visceral feeling that I do not know, nor will I ever, know what I&amp;rsquo;m doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selecting the first item from an array</title>
      <link>https://burkeholland.github.io/posts/select-one-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 05:27:23 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://burkeholland.github.io/posts/select-one-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, in life, you just want one of something. Not two. Never two. Just one. Like a toothbrush. Or a flu shot. Or a pug. Dear god, trust me, you do not want more than one pug. It&amp;rsquo;s like a choir of snoring with flatulance on backup vocals.
This is common in database queries, too. I mean, the desire to just get one result. Not the flatulance. Although it might be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying a Nuxt app to Azure</title>
      <link>https://burkeholland.github.io/posts/thank-u-nuxt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 19:21:49 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://burkeholland.github.io/posts/thank-u-nuxt/</guid>
      <description>Summary: Nuxt apps with &amp;ldquo;server-side rendering&amp;rdquo; require a Node server, so you need to deploy them to Azure App Service. If you are using Nuxt apps in SPA mode, you can (and should) deploy them to Azure Storage.
Check out the links below for more details&amp;hellip; Deploy to Azure App Service Deploy a static website to Azure 
Ariana Grande once said, &amp;ldquo;One taught me patience. And one taught me pain&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This is how to easily deploy a static site to Azure</title>
      <link>https://burkeholland.github.io/posts/static-site-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 06:48:24 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://burkeholland.github.io/posts/static-site-azure/</guid>
      <description>Over the weekend I bought my first new vehicle ever: A red moped. That was the only thing available at my price point.
What a glorious thing it is! The wind whips over your body at a stunning 35 mph and you are alone with your thoughts. You ponder the finer points of the universe: existential questions like, “Do I look stupid on this thing”, “How many bugs can you eat before you die” and “How many ways can I deploy a static site to Azure”?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Urlist — An application study in Serverless and Azure</title>
      <link>https://burkeholland.github.io/posts/the-urlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 09:30:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://burkeholland.github.io/posts/the-urlist/</guid>
      <description>Today we are pleased to announce that we (Burke Holland and Cecil Phillip) are releasing a project called “The Urlist”. You can access it starting today at theurlist.com.
The Urlist is an application that lets you create lists of url’s that you can share with others. Get it? A list of URL’s? The Urlist? Listen, naming things is hard and all the good domains are already taken.
This project was born out of a realization that I was ending my presentations with a slide full of links to additional resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitLens with Eric Amodio</title>
      <link>https://burkeholland.github.io/posts/git-lens-eric/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 10:11:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://burkeholland.github.io/posts/git-lens-eric/</guid>
      <description>There are only two kinds of people in the world: those who are utterly confused by Git, and those who refuse to admit it.
 
Well, ok, there are probably some people who understand it, but I’m definitely not one of them.
As a result, people like me (which is most of us — zero evidence to prove that so just accept it as fact and let it wash over you) tend to learn the base amount of Git that we need to get by (clone, pull, add, commit) and the rest we try really hard to avoid because we have zero confidence that we’ll be able to do it without breaking literally everything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Three Laws of Serverless</title>
      <link>https://burkeholland.github.io/posts/signs-of-serverless/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://burkeholland.github.io/posts/signs-of-serverless/</guid>
      <description>A wise man once said this about Serverless&amp;hellip;
So wise! So profound. So obnoxiously vain to use your own quote.
&amp;ldquo;Serverless&amp;rdquo;, is a buzzword. We can&amp;rsquo;t seem to agree on what it actaully means, so it ends up meaning nothing at all. It&amp;rsquo; like &amp;ldquo;cloud&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;dynamic&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;synergy&amp;rdquo;. You just wait for the right time in a meeting to drop it, walk to the board and draw a Venn Diagram, and then just sit back and wait for your well-deserved promotion.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>