<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Burke Knows Words</title>
    <link>http://burkeholland.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Burke Knows Words</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://burkeholland.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cosmos CRUD</title>
      <link>http://burkeholland.github.io/cosmos-crud/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 16:24:55 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://burkeholland.github.io/cosmos-crud/</guid>
      <description>Cosmos DB JavaScript SDK is clean - I like it. But I feel like I always end up forgetting how to CRUD.
For the uninitiated in database street-slang, CRUD means Create, Read, Update And Delete. Feel free to use that if you find yourself in a turf war or dance-off.
Well, I take that back. I can “read” everything purty gud. Actually, I can “create” as well. It’s the retrieving of one item that always throw me off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VS Code for the complete beginner</title>
      <link>http://burkeholland.github.io/vs-code-complete-beginner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://burkeholland.github.io/vs-code-complete-beginner/</guid>
      <description>Have you never used a coding tool in your life? Do you barely know how to code, or not know how to code at all? Would you like to learn, but everything looks so tedious and complicated that it hardly seems worth sacrificing valuable gaming time? Do you strongly dislike blog posts that start with a series of rhetorical questions?
Well, my friend, you have come to the right place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to configure a root domain in an Azure Static Web App</title>
      <link>http://burkeholland.github.io/static-app-root-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 14:55:57 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://burkeholland.github.io/static-app-root-domain/</guid>
      <description>Azure Static Web Apps is a new Azure service for hosting static web applications. Azure is very literal when they name things. Want Storage? You need Azure Storage. Want a Serverless function? Azure Functions. Need to host a static web app? AZURE STATIC WEB APPS.
Static Web Apps is currently in preview, which means not all features that need to be there are quite there yet. One of the features that is currently AFK is support for root domains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professional quality audio with the Blue Yeti, GarageBand and Screenflow</title>
      <link>http://burkeholland.github.io/audio-how-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 16:06:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://burkeholland.github.io/audio-how-to/</guid>
      <description>One of the best things you can do to improve the quality of your screencasts, is improve the quality of your audio.
I’m assuming that unless your name is “Dr. Dre”, you probably do not have a professional sound studio in your basement full of high-end equipment and expensive software. And if you’re like me, you don’t even have a basement.
What I do have is a Blue Yeti microphone, GarageBand and a copy of Screenflow that I can barely afford.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trimming expenses on The Urlist with Azure Cosmos DB Free Tier</title>
      <link>http://burkeholland.github.io/cosmos-free-tier/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 16:09:16 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://burkeholland.github.io/cosmos-free-tier/</guid>
      <description>Summary: We migrated theurlist.com to the new Cosmos DB Free Tier and shaved ~35$ per month off of our Azure bill. Cosmos DB Free Tier gives you 400 RU/s for free every month. This should be more than enough for most small projects. 
Get Azure Cosmos DB Free Tier 
 
theurlist.com is a project that I wrote with my colleague Cecil Phillip last year. We wanted to see if we could build a site on Azure that was two things…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create a Reminder on Apple Watch without creating a Reminder</title>
      <link>http://burkeholland.github.io/apple-watch-reminders/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 14:34:39 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://burkeholland.github.io/apple-watch-reminders/</guid>
      <description>I have an Apple Watch (not cellular), and I love it. Not just because it lets everyone know that I’m better than them, but also for it’s ability to sync and store all of my audio to be used offline. I can download my music (including Apple Music), podcasts and now even Audible books to my Watch and take it all with me when I exercise. This means I don’t have to strap my iPhone to arm like giant medievil shield.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 3 Laws of Serverless</title>
      <link>http://burkeholland.github.io/laws-of-serverless/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 16:43:32 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://burkeholland.github.io/laws-of-serverless/</guid>
      <description>A wise man once said this about Serverless…
So wise! So profound. So obnoxiously vain to use your own quote.
“Serverless”, is a buzzword. We can’t seem to agree on what it actaully means, so it ends up meaning nothing at all. Much like “cloud” or “dynamic” or “synergy”. You just wait for the right time in a meeting to drop it, walk to the board and draw a Venn Diagram, and then just sit back and wait for your well-deserved promotion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSAP, Webpack and invalid tweens</title>
      <link>http://burkeholland.github.io/invalid-tween/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 16:51:54 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://burkeholland.github.io/invalid-tween/</guid>
      <description>Before I forget, I wanted to document for posterity how I lost about 4 hours yesterday to gsap/webpack issue.
I was working on a Vue project (CLI) with some gsap powered animations that I did not write. Not having written them, I can confess that I have no idea what they are or what they do. Any time I see the word “Tween”, I get flashbacks to actual Flash timelines and this very visceral feeling that I do not know, nor will I ever, know what I’m doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selecting the first item from an array</title>
      <link>http://burkeholland.github.io/select-one-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 17:00:11 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://burkeholland.github.io/select-one-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, in life, you just want one of something. Not two. Never two. Just one. Like a toothbrush. Or a flu shot. Or a pug. Dear god, trust me, you do not want more than one pug. It’s like a choir of snoring with flatulance on backup vocals.
This is common in database queries, too. I mean, the desire to just get one result. Not the flatulance. Although it might be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying a Nuxt App to Azure</title>
      <link>http://burkeholland.github.io/thank-you-nuxt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 17:04:42 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://burkeholland.github.io/thank-you-nuxt/</guid>
      <description>Summary: Nuxt apps with “server-side rendering” require a Node server, so you need to deploy them to Azure App Service. If you are using Nuxt apps in SPA mode, you can (and should) deploy them to Azure Storage. Check out the links below for more details…
Deploy to Azure App Service Deploy a static website to Azure  
Ariana Grande once said, “One taught me patience. And one taught me pain”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This is how to easily deploy a static site to Azure</title>
      <link>http://burkeholland.github.io/static-site-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 08:36:49 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://burkeholland.github.io/static-site-azure/</guid>
      <description>Over the weekend I bought my first new vehicle ever: A red moped. That was the only thing available at my price point.
What a glorious thing it is! The wind whips over your body at a stunning 35 mph and you are alone with your thoughts. You ponder the finer points of the universe: existential questions like, “Do I look stupid on this thing”, “How many bugs can you eat before you die” and “How many ways can I deploy a static site to Azure”?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Urlist — An application study in Serverless and Azure</title>
      <link>http://burkeholland.github.io/the-urlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 08:47:17 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://burkeholland.github.io/the-urlist/</guid>
      <description>Today we are pleased to announce that we (Burke Holland and Cecil Phillip) are releasing a project called “The Urlist”. You can access it starting today at theurlist.com.
The Urlist is an application that lets you create lists of url’s that you can share with others. Get it? A list of URL’s? The Urlist? Listen, naming things is hard and all the good domains are already taken.
This project was born out of a realization that I was ending my presentations with a slide full of links to additional resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitLens with Eric Amodio</title>
      <link>http://burkeholland.github.io/git-lens-eric/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 08:49:37 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://burkeholland.github.io/git-lens-eric/</guid>
      <description>There are only two kinds of people in the world: those who are utterly confused by Git, and those who refuse to admit it.
![](https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*hvJgiUToHU6NEGzy397LbA.jpeg) Well, ok, there are probably some people who understand it, but I’m definitely not one of them.
As a result, people like me (which is most of us — zero evidence to prove that so just accept it as fact and let it wash over you) tend to learn the base amount of Git that we need to get by (clone, pull, add, commit) and the rest we try really hard to avoid because we have zero confidence that we’ll be able to do it without breaking literally everything.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
